ZACHARY WIDENER

Skilled Journeyman Desktop Support/Network Administration

Lake Charles, LA

zacharywidener@gmail.com

239.839.4255

Highly motivated journeyman with 10 years of experience providing excellent technical support for roughly 1400 users in a corporate environment. 5 years of experience supervising two workstation techs. Always eager to learn new skills while effectively demonstrating current skill set to provide assistance in resolving simple to complex tasks ranging from workstation support to network support.

Willing to relocate to: Oregon - Washington State

Authorized to work in the US for any employer



WORK EXPERIENCE

Analyst II - User Support

Westlake Chemical - Westlake, LA December 2014 to Present

I am currently a User Support Analyst for the corporate desktop support/user services team in the IT department at Westlake Chemical Corp. My role is to provide end-user support for a myriad of IT-related issues, including but not limited to: hardware, software, networking, mobile device support, Active Directory admin, server admin.

- Assisted with Desktop team project of Win7 to Win10 workstation OS upgrade of ~1050 workstations.
- 5 years of experience supervising two contract workstation techs. Ensuring they meet the SLA on their tickets, stay focused on the task at hand, training/mentoring them, monthly updates/reviews.
- Involved in migrating ~100 Windows Mobile OS handheld devices/scanners from MSP server to SOTI server.
- Actively supporting ~1400 employees/contractors across 7 different locations either on-site or remotely.
- Responsible for the procurement of all IT-related hardware and software for my local site via SAP.

Computer Technologist

Levingston Group - Westlake, LA July 2012 to December 2014

Contract IT workstation technician at Westlake Chemical providing end-user support for hardware and software, printer troubleshooting, network troubleshooting, imaging new workstations, setting up the equipment for the users, help desk support.

- Assisted in migrating over 1,000 workstations to a new company domain from Axiall Corporation to Westlake Chemical.
- Part of a team traveling to different company sites in Louisiana and Mississippi upgrading ~500 workstations from Windows XP to Win7. Includes backing up user data, implementing the company OS image, any user support needed after the OS upgrade.

Computer Support Specialist

City of Lake Charles - Lake Charles, LA December 2010 to July 2012 This position started out as an internship and evolved into a permanent part-time position. Responsible for end-user computer and network support at City Hall, Fire Stations, Public Works, Waste Water treatment facilities, and 911 dispatch centers.



EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Computer Information Systems - Cyber Security

Northwestern State University - Natchitoches, LA June 2017 to Present

Associate in Computer Information Systems - Networking Specialist

SOWELA Technical Community College - Lake Charles, LA June 2008 to December 2010



SKILLS

- Active Directory
- Desktop Support
- LAN
- Network Support
- Mobile Devices
- Help Desk
- Computer Networking
- Microsoft Office
- Server Management
- VMWare
- SCCM
- Windows Server
- Remote Access Software
- Wireless
- Software Troubleshooting
- Technical Support
- Operating Systems
- SAP (5 years)
- Citrix
- Network Administration
- Microsoft Exchange